Well, let me give you a massive welcome
to the definitive AI coder course. This
is the missing manual. Over the course
of three weeks, I'm going to take you on
this extraordinary journey that will end
up with you being an expert at agentic
engineering. But first, a word of
caution. You need to buckle up. You need
to strap in because I have a wild ride
in store for you. This is going to be a
roller coaster. I have so much to show
you. Let me tell you all about it. It is
standard fair with these kinds of
courses. A good way to go about doing it
is to begin with the objectives,
introduce myself, give you the
curriculum and the logistics. Except I
don't do that. If you've been on any of
my courses before, you know perfectly
well that I always like to start with
instant gratification. Let's roll up
sleeves. Let's build something together.
There'll be plenty of time to come back
later and do all of that stuff. In the
next three weeks, we're going to be
working with a number of different AI
products that generate code. But for
today, we're going to start with Cursor.
Super popular, very easy to use, and it
has a free trial if you haven't used it
before. So, that's what we're going to
use. If you've used Cursor before and
you've you've spent all of the free
trial and you don't want to use it
anymore, you don't need to. You can just
watch what I do right now or you could
follow along with another product if you
like. We're just going to do something
super simple because we want to use an
AI to generate code right away. and then
we'll get on with the course. Let's go
do it. And so the first thing to do is
to bring up a browser. I'm in Chrome
right here. And I'm going to cursor.com.
Cursor cur ss o r.com. Press enter. And
here we are. We are in cursor's website.
It says it's built to make you
extraordinarily productive. Cursor is
the best way to code with AI. Well,
we'll be the judge of that. We'll be
using a few of these and we can decide
ourselves. But for now, we are going to
use cursor. So the first thing to do is
to download it and install it locally
which we will do now. And it's worth
keeping an eye on the course resources
which will be linked in the platform to
make sure that nothing's changed.
There's no extra instructions as you go.
But it should be pretty simple. You
start by going to download and you can
download the right version for your
platform. For me that I'm on a Mac, an
ARM Mac, an M1 Mac. Uh but you might
pick Mac, Windows or Linux. And actually
on the landing page probably the button
right here is allowing you immediately
to download the versions for your
platform. So download that file. I'll
press it now to download for Mac and
then you will launch it on your computer
once it's downloaded. And just for the
PC people to show you here I am in a
Microsoft Edge browser. I've gone to
cursor.com and download for Windows is
the default button which I'm pressing
right now too. And that's now
downloading for the PC as well. And so
then on Windows once it's downloaded you
open the file the usual stuff. You say
you accept the agreement. You press next
and then you just pick the normal
defaults. Uh including that that last
one in particular add to path is
important. And then next and then
install and cursor will be installed on
your PC. On a Mac you just drag the box
over to applications and you're done.
And when that's done we will then get
started with cursor. And the first time
you come into Cursor, you should be
prompted to sign in or sign up. And of
course, you're going to want to sign up
if you don't already have a Cursor
account, which should be free for the
first few weeks, which is all that we
need it for. And what if you get this
screen, you can just press the signin
button there. Or if you don't see this
screen, you should be able to go to the
file menu and say new menu, new window,
and then you will see this screen. And
then you press the signin button. It
brings up a cursor window in the browser
like this. Sign into cursor. continue to
sign in and then you can say don't have
an account sign up and this is the
screen where you then enter your details
answer a few questions and then you will
have an account with cursor that you can
sign into as I say it should be there
have a trial period should be free for a
couple of weeks which is all that we
need to give it a good test run if you
already have a cursor account so much
the better okay I will see you over in
cursor if you have any problems with
this do look at the course resources or
shoot me a question so I and help you
out. Okay. So then when you launch
cursor, this is what you see. You see
the cursor screen. If you don't see
exactly this screen, go to the file menu
and choose new window. And then this is
what you'll get. It may not say pro here
if you don't have a pro account if
you're on the free trial account. And if
you see login here, you press that
login. Again, any problems, message me.
All right. The first thing we're going
to do is open a project. And I'm going
to show you what it looks like on a Mac
and then on a PC. So cursor is based on
VS Code. And you may be very familiar
with this already if you use VS Code,
but open a project really means I want
to select a directory on my computer.
That directory will be used to house
everything related to this project. And
it's typical for people to to start in
their home directory. Mine is called ED.
And then to go to a a folder called
projects where you have your own
projects. And if you don't have such a
folder, you press new folder to create
projects. But I do have such a folder.
Here it is. And here I've got lots of
projects. Here are all my projects. And
what I can do now is press new folder.
And I can type out instant uh for the
name of this instant project. And press
create. And here I am inside instant.
And then I press open. And it opens the
project called instant. And you'll tell
that because it says instant in block
capitals right there. Okay. Now, let me
show you the same thing on a PC. So here
I am on cursor on the PC. If it says
sign in right there, I can click there
to go through and sign into cursor. Uh
otherwise I can press open project, it
comes up. This is the kind of browser on
a PC. I'm in my home folder again. Ed, I
can create a new folder or I can go into
projects that already exists. That's how
you create a new folder. I'll go into
projects and I can create a new folder.
I can call it instant. And there is
instant. I can go into instant and then
say select folder. And here we are. We
are now inside instant. You can see it
says instant on the top left. That means
we've got it right. And uh this is the
beginning of cursor on a PC. Okay. So
just to orient you on cursor, we're
seeing like three panes here. On the
left, this is showing the whole file
system of our project of instant and
it's very empty. We don't have many
files here right now. Uh we will do very
soon. In the middle here is the main
place where we'll see code. And on the
right, this is where we chat with an
agent. And if you're not seeing these
three panes, then there's various, if
you go to the view menu, there's an
appearance submen, and you can toggle
around different things until you do see
these two panes. Uh, I'm sure you'll
figure it out. Otherwise, message me.
Okay. What we're now going to do is
explore using the thing on the right,
the agent, to actually do some work for
us for the first time. Now look,
something that I feel very strongly
about which which I have on all of my
courses is that when we build projects
together and I like building projects
together when we do it, I like them to
have real world commercial impact. I
like to build things which are actually
valuable which perhaps you could think
of monetizing at some point or use as
like a springboard for something else
that you want to build. So for me being
business relevant, business first is
super important and invariably I like my
projects to have business impact. But
but not today. Today is going to be an
exception. The only exception. Every one
of the projects we do on this course are
going to have important business impact
except for this one. Today we're just
going to have some fun because what
better way to start than with something
a bit entertaining. So, we're going to
start with a fun project. But don't
worry if you're more all business. It's
going to be all business after this
point. Okay, let me show this to you.
When we click in on the right over here,
we can talk to an LLM. We can talk to a
language model, to an agent, and have it
do some work for us. And if you're
wondering what what all of these things
are, don't worry. Tomorrow I'm going to
go through a lot of the the constructs,
agents, how they work, what they do, and
so on. And if you know all this already,
well then you've seen this before, but
we're just going to have some fun. It's
going to build from here. Okay. So, what
we put in here is going to be a message
to our coding uh agent, like our
sidekick that's going to work with us on
this. And just below here, we can choose
what model are we going to use, what AI
is going to sit behind this and work on
it for us. And depending on your plan,
you might not be allowed to choose. It
might be set to auto, which means cursor
gets to choose. uh but um on the plan
that I'm on, I can actually choose and I
have chosen GPT 5.2 codecs, one of the
strongest models that there are as of
today. So that's the one that we will
use for now. And in here, I'm going to
put the request that I have for this AI
to work with me. Okay. And this is the
request. Please build a website for a 3D
firstperson shooter game in an arena
against one computer opponent controlled
by arrow keys and spacebar to shoot. All
right, I'm sending that off and so
should you. And off it goes doing stuff.
It's it's you can see the actions it's
taken written here. It's planning the
next moves. It's it's uh listed. It's
exploring and off it goes doing stuff.
And it's writing a file. a file just got
written called index.html or it's in the
middle of writing it. Now, it's possible
that it's going to ask you for
permission to do various things in which
case, as long as you're happy with it,
you should say yes. Um, but it may well
not like mine. It depends on your on
your settings, but I think I believe the
default will be the same as me and it
would just go off and do this stuff,
creating files, writing stuff. And I am
using GPT 5.2 codecs and you might be
using a different model. And the thing
is and something that you'll get
familiar with on this course is that
every one of us will have a different
experience. There is some uncertainty
here that it is not necessarily
predictable what happens next. But this
agent is off. It's doing stuff and it's
working on index.html.